凱文·科斯特納
安迪·加西亞
羅伯特·德·尼祿
肖恩·康納利
片名: 鐵面無私
1930年 禁酒令使芝加哥變成戰場
幫派人物爭地盤搶權力
建立億萬元計的私酒王國
他們用暴力手段來鞏固他們的勢力
這是一個無法紀的時代
梟雄 艾爾·卡彭 不可一世
An article, which I believe appeared in a newspaper, asked why,
艾爾 報紙上有篇文章
since it would seem that you are in effect the Mayor of Chicago,
事實上你等於是芝加哥市長
you're not simply being appointed to that position.
你只是差一紙委任令而己
Well, I tell ya, it's touching. Like a lot of things in life,
我告訴你 這很動人
we laugh because it's funny, and we laugh because it's true.
有許多事可笑 因為那是真的
Some people say, reformers here say:
有些人說:
"Put that man in jail, what does he think he is doing? "
拿那人下獄 他自以為他在幹什麼
What I hope I'm doing, and here's where your paper's got a point,
同樣的 我在幹什麼
is I'm responding to the will of the people.
你們報紙要弄清楚 我是在反映民眾意見
People are gonna drink. We all know that. All I do is act on that.
人們要喝酒 你知道我知道 大家都知道 我只是知而後行
And all this talk of bootlegging. What is bootlegging?
說什麼販賣私酒? 什麼叫販賣私酒?
On the boat it's bootlegging, on Lake Shore Drive it's hospitality.
我不是在賣私酒
I'm a businessman.
我只是個生意人
Your reputation is that you control your business through violence.
你以暴力控制生意 怎麼說
That those that don't purchase your product are dealt with violently.
把你的貨強迫推銷出去
It's all right.
沒關係
I grew up in a tough neighbourhood.
我在惡劣環境下長大
We used to say, "You can get further with a kind word and a gun"
我們常說:槍桿
"than you can with just a kind word."
勝過許多好話
And in that neighbourhood it might've been true.
在我那種環境這是真的
And sometimes your reputation follows you.
然後你會贏得名謄
There is violence in Chicago, but not by me
芝加哥的確有暴力存在 但並不在於我
and not by anybody I employ. Because it's not good business.
或是我雇用的人 我告訴你們原因? 因為那不是好生意
Leave us alone down here, we've got everything we need.
走開 不要打攪我們 我們不需要任何東西
The green beer you're peddling aingt any good.
你那些東西毫無用處
It's not supposed to be good. It's supposed to be bought.
很有用的 很值得一買
I'm not buying any.
我什麼也不買
Don't worry about it, Pops, we won't come back.
別擔心 我們不會回來了
How's everyone at your house today? They're fine.
你家裡的人都好嗎 他們很好
Is your Mama well? She has a little cold.
你媽好呢 她有點感冒
Oh, she does?
是嗎?
I'm sorry to hear that. But she'll be all right.
我很難過聽到這事 她不要緊的
There you go. Thank you.
給你 謝謝
That's all right, sweetie. You be careful crossing the street.
不客氣 小可愛 過馬路時要當心 告訴你媽
Mister! You tell your Mama that...
先生…先生
Hey, Mister! Wait!
先生 等一下
Mister! Wait! You forgot your brief...
先生 等一下 你忘了你的手提箱
“私酒戰爭屠殺十歲女孩”
Yes, I heard it on the radio.
是的 我聽到收音機廣播了
I know.
我瞭解
Now it's time to go to work.
上班時間到了
You'll make a good first impression.
你要給人第一眼好印象
I love you, Eliot.
我愛你 艾略特
Now, shoo.
走吧
Eliot Ness, Special Agent of the Treasury Department.
艾略特.奈斯 財政部特派員
Mr Ness. Thank you, Chief.
奈斯 謝謝你 局長
At the request of the City of Chicago,
基於芝加哥市民要求
the Department of the Treasury has inaugurated a programme
聯邦政府令財政部成立專案
to deal with the flow of illegal liquor and the violence it creates.
制止私酒之販賣及其所引發之暴力
Mr Ness! Of what does this programme consist?
奈斯先生 這個計畫包括什麼
I and other agents of the Treasury will be working
我和其它財政部專員將與
with the Chicago Police...
警方及其它單位合作
Isn't it just another showpiece programme?
這是否又是一次官樣文章
What do you think of prohibition? Do you drink, Mr Ness?
你對禁酒令有何看法 你喝不喝酒? 奈斯先生
Come on, answer the questions. It's not just a showpiece.
奈斯先生 回答問題 這不是官樣文章
And I'll tell you how I feel about prohibition.
我來告訴你們 我對禁酒令的看法
It is the law of the land.
那是國家的法律
Do you consider yourself a crusader, is that it?
你自認你是位掃蕩戰士嗎? 奈斯先生
What qualifications do you have for the job?
你有何專長擔此大任
Do you have any political ambitions?
你可有政治野心
All right, boys, I think that's enough.
好了 今天到此為止
What are your real plans? What have you got coming up?
你有何計畫? 打算如何著手
You'll have to read about it in the paper.
你去看報紙吧
Let me ride along with you. No. Can't help you.
讓我和你同去 我們會配合得很好 不 愛莫能助
Mr Ness, Lieutenant Alderson, the Flying Squad.
奈斯先生 奧德森中尉 飛騎警隊
Are you ready to meet the men?
你準備會見弟兄了嗎
Yes, I am.
是的 我準備好了
“預備室武器登記”
I have one more thing to say.
我還有一件事要說
I know that many of you take a drink.
我知道你們很多人喝酒
What you've done before today is not my concern.
今天以前的事我不管
But now we must be pure, and I want you to stop.
但今後要乾淨 停止喝酒
It's not a question of whether it's 'a harmless drink'. It may well be.
問題不在於喝酒是否傷身
But it's against the law.
而在於那是違反法律 各位
And as we are going to enforce the law, we must do first by example.
我們要厲行法律便要以身作則
Are there any questions?
有疑問嗎?
Good. The Department of the Treasury's had
很好
a man undercover here for some time now.
財政部有位密探臥底一段時間了
We've received word from this informant
我們接獲情報
that a large shipment of Canadian whiskey has arrived in Chicago.
昨天自加拿大運來了大批私酒
So I hope that you have signed on for some action.
所以我希望你們準備一下 我們要去抓他們了
Remember, the liquor cases are marked with the red maple leaf.
記住私酒箱上有紅色記號
The Treasury Agent is in a grey suit with a white scarf.
密探穿的是灰大衣白圍巾
He is not to be arrested. A grey suit and a white scarf.
不要抓他 灰大衣 白圍巾
That's it. Are your men ready? Yes, sir. They are.
就這樣 你的人準備好了嗎 是的 先生 都準備好了
At ease. Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
稍息 準備對付壞蛋
How are we doing Okay.
準備如何? 好了
Want part of a sandwich? No, thank you, sir.
來點三明治 不 謝謝 長官
You nervous? No, sir.
你緊張嗎 不 長官
Been with the unit long? A short while.
你在這單位很久了 才一陣子
I suppose we all want to do well. Yes, sir.
我想大家都想把事做好 是的 長官
A message from my wife.
我太太寫的字條
You married? Yes, sir, I am.
你結婚了? 是的
Nice to be married, huh?
結婚不錯 是吧
Just follow me.
跟我來
Oh, God... Federal officer. Hands in the air.
聯邦官員 手舉起來
Get 'em up. Drop it.
聯邦官員 手舉起來 東西放下
Damn it, I can't, it'll break.
我不能 會砸壞
Mr Ness. Look, I was just...
奈斯先生 我只是
Geez, I'm sorry.
對不起
Listen, I can do a lot for you, what you're trying to do.
聽著 我可以為你做許多事情
I get the big scoop, you make a big splash.
我搶大新聞 替你宣揚
Get some support. What do you say? Let's be real, let me help you.
爭取新聞界支持如何? 讓我幫你 如何?
Okay. Just shut up.
閉嘴
All right now... Let's do some good!
好了 各位 我們大幹一場吧
Hold it right there!
站住別動
Federal officer. You're under arrest for violations of the Volstead Act.
聯邦官員 你們因違反禁酒令被捕了
Let's cover the doors! Don't let anybody out!
關上門 誰都不能出去
Preseuski.
普勒斯基
I'm here with permission. Who gave you permission?
借過 借過 我有許可
Mr Ness! Sorry, let him through here.
奈斯先生 不要緊 讓他進來
Let him through here.
讓他進來
You want to take your picture, take it now.
你要拍照就現在拍吧
You ready? Ready.
Get him out of here.
帶他出去
Tear the place apart! I mean now, get him out!
把這兒拆散 現在 帶他出去
That means you, too.
你也出去
“緝酒戰士奈斯灰頭土臉”
“差勁的艾略特.奈斯”
“我非常以你為榮”
Now, what do you think you're doing?
你在幹什麼?
You want to throw garbage? Throw it in the goddamn trash basket.
要丟垃圾丟到垃圾袋中
Don't you have more important things to do?
你沒有更重要的事做嗎?
Yeah.But I'm not doing them right now.
有 但我不必現在去做
Do we understand each other?
我們彼此都明白
Okay, pal, why the Mohaska?
好了 朋友 別亂動
Why are you packing the gun? I'm a Treasury Officer.
你為何帶著槍 我是財政部特派員
All right.Just remember what we talked about now.
好吧 我沒空和你閒扯
Hey... Wait a minute!
等一下
What the hell kind of police do you have in this goddamn city?
這個城市的員警是怎麼回事?
You just turned your back on an armed man.
你竟背對著位帶槍的人
You're a Treasury officer. I just told you I was.
你是位財政部官員 何以見得 那只是我說的而己
Who would claim to be that, who was not?
誰願冒充財政部官員 除了瘋子外
What's your name and unit?
你的姓名和單位
It's right here.
在這上面
You got a beef? What is it?
你有牢騷 怎麼回事?
How did you know I had a gun?
你怎麼知道我有帶槍
What do you want, a free lesson in police work?
你要什麼? 學會員警的絕招嗎
No.
不
Are you okay, pal?
你沒事吧? 朋友
I had a rough day on the job.
我工作不順利
Are you going home now? I was about to.
你要回家了嗎 我正要回去
Well, then, you just fulfilled the first rule of law enforcement.
你已做到了執法者規則第一條
Make sure when your shift is over you go home alive.
確保能活著下班回家
Here endeth the lesson.
第一課結束
$100, 000 for 40 barrels. Make sure there are no empties.
總數十萬元 一共四十桶 別有空的
I'm gonna give you the ledger, everything is in the book.
我給你的底帳都在帳簿裡
55 gallons to the barrel.
桶是五十五加侖
It's Eddie. Come in, Eddie.
我是艾迪 進來 艾迪
“緝酒戰士奈斯灰頭土臉”
So, he gets into the snowplough, and he says, "Let's do some good".
他坐進除雪車裡說道 “我們好好幹一場”
And then, we bust through...
然後我們破門而入
“緝酒戰士奈斯灰頭土臉”
Mr Ness? Yes?
奈斯先生? 什麼事
I came here to thank you.
我是來謝謝你的
It was...my little girl that got killed with that bomb.
被炸死的小女孩是我的女兒
I'm sorry. Please.
我很難過 請進
I'm...l'm so sorry.
我很難過
You see, it's...because I know that you have children, too.
你瞭解 因為我知道你也有小孩
And that this is real for you, that these men cause us tragedy.
你會真心認為這是件悲傷的事
And I know that you will put a stop to them.
你要阻止他們
And you do that, now.
What do you want? I'd like to talk to you.
你要幹什麼 我想和你談談
Come in.
請進
I need a small group of men, handpicked, starting with you.
我要找一批人 首先找上的是你
Ness! I am just a poor beat cop.
奈斯 奈斯 我只是個可憐的巡夜員警
Now, how can I help you? Just work with me.
我如何能幫助你 只要和我一起辦事
But why should I, though? Because you're a good cop.
我為什麼要 因為你是好員警
How do you know that? You told me.
你怎麼知道 你告訴我的
If I'm such a good cop...
我若是好員警
How come I'm walking the beat, then, at my age?
我還會在這年紀仍擔任巡夜嗎?
Do you want to tell me?
你想告訴我嗎
Well, maybe I'm that Whore with a Heart of Gold.
也許我是心地善良
Or The One Good Cop in the Bad Town? Is that what you want to hear?
罪惡圈裡唯一的好員警 你想聽這些嗎
I didn't ask you, and I don't care!
我沒要求你
You want to stay on the beat? You do that.
我不在乎 你要去巡夜就請便
If you'd like to come with me, I need your help.
你願跟我一起嗎? 我需要幫助
I'm asking you for help.
我在請你幫忙
Well...that's the thing you fear, isn't it?
你害怕什麼
Mr Ness, I wish I'd met you ten years and...twenty pounds ago.
奈斯先生 希望在十年前就遇到你 或是體重輕二十磅前
But...I just think it got... more important to me...to stay alive.
現在對我較重要的便是保住老命
And that's why I'm walking the beat. Thank you, no.
所以我甘心擔任巡夜 謝謝 我不幹
That's good, Andy. Let's start up the thing and take a little ride.
來 開車吧 我們去兜風
I wanna hear that Stutz Bearcat engine, boy!
我要聽一下熊貓牌引擎的聲音
Yeah, let me open the door here. Yeah, go ahead.
好 讓我開車門 好的
Whoopsy daisy, pick up the door there, Andy.
你快去把門撿起來
Throw it in the back seat. Now, let me get the thing started.
把它扔到後座 讓我發動引擎
Yeah, start it up, Andy.
對 發動引擎吧
Holy mackerel, Andy! Listen to that Bearcat motor!
天啊! 聽聽引擎聲
Yeah, it sounds like the bear is chasing that cat all round it!
聽起來就像大熊不停追著小貓
Andy! She's boiling over!
引擎過熱冒煙了
Mr Ness? Yes.
奈斯先生?
Oscar Wallace.
奧斯卡.華萊士
I've been assigned here by the Washington Bureau.
華盛頓派我來的
Really? Yes.
很好
Well, I'm glad to have you here, Mr Wallace. Would you excuse me?
我很高興你加入…對不起
We are a little in the dark here, but any ideas you may have...
我們現在一籌莫展 你有建議嗎?
Well, actually, yes, sir, I do.
是的 我有
And the one I want to try first... is this.
我首先要試的便是這個
He has not filed a return since 1926.
他自1926年就沒有申報過
A return...? An income tax return.
申報 申報所得稅
Income tax. Yes, sir.
申報所得稅? 是的 先生
What do you do at the Bureau? Oh, I'm an accountant.
你在局裡是做什麼的 華萊士我是會計
An accountant? Yes, and the Bureau sent me here...
會計? 是的 總局派我來此
Would you excuse me?
失陪一下
Please.
坐吧
Okay. Let's go.
好了 我們走
Where are we going? These walls have ears.
去哪裡 這裡隔牆有耳
You said you wanted to know how to get Capone.
你說你想知道 如何扳倒卡彭
Do you really want to get him? You see what I'm saying?
你真的要捉他
What are you prepared to do? Everything within the law.
你明白我的意思 你打算怎麼做? 一切合法的行動
And then what are you prepared to do?
若不成 你又有何打算?
If you open the ball on these people,
如果你打算向他們開戰
you must be prepared to go all the way.
你就要一直戰鬥下去
Because they won't give up the fight until one of you is dead.
因為他們非和你拼個你死我活不可
I want to get Capone. I don't know how.
我要捉卡彭 我不知該如何下手
Here's how you get Capone: he pulls a knife, you pull a gun.
要捉卡彭 就要比他強他拔刀 你就拔槍
He sends one of yours to hospital, you send one of his to the morgue!
他傷了你的部下 你就宰了他的爪牙
That's the Chicago way! And that's how you get Capone.
那就是芝加哥的規則 那就是捉卡彭的方法
Now, do you want to do that?
你能那樣幹嗎
Are you ready to do that?
你準備好那樣幹了嗎
I'm making you a deal. Do you want this deal?
我提供你這建議 你要不要接受?
I have sworn to put this man away,
我已發誓要將他繩之以法
with any and all legal means at my disposal, and I will do so.
以合法手段 盡我所能去達成
Well, the Lord hates a coward.
天主憎惡懦夫
Do you know what a blood oath is, Mr Ness?
你可知血誓之意義
Yes. Good. 'Cause you just took one.
是的 很好 你剛得了個宣過血誓的人
How do you think Capone knew about your raid the other night?
你明白那晚的突襲何以不成功?
Somebody on the cops told him. Right. Welcome to Chicago.
有人通風報信 對 你開竅了
This town stinks like a whorehouse at low tide.
芝加哥就像娼館一樣污穢
First, who can you trust? Nobody. The cops, nobody.
首先的是 你能相信誰 沒有人 員警? 沒有任何人
'Cause nobody wants you here. Then why are you helping me?
這裡沒有人喜歡你 那你為何肯幫我
Because I swore to uphold the law.
因為我曾宣誓維護法律執行
And if you believe that, I'll tell you another.
你要相信的話 我再告訴你另一件事
Now, who can you trust? I can trust nobody.
你能信任誰? 我誰也不信任
That's the sorry truth. Then, where are we gonna get help?
那是件悲哀的事 我們誰也不能信任的話要如何取得幫助
If you're afraid of getting a rotten apple, don't go to the barrel.
如果你不想拿到爛蘋果 那就別拿桶子裡的
Get it off the tree.
去摘樹上的
Get it off the tree...
去樹上摘
Finger out of the trigger guard! Eject those cartridges!
手放在扳機罩 彈出彈夾
Lay the revolver on the ledge and stand back!
放下左輪 退後一步
About face!
向後轉
Barry! I want you to meet Mr Eliot Ness.
賴特 見過艾略特.奈斯
Treasury Department. How are you? We need a recruit for extended duty.
財政部特派員 你好 我們需要人手
He is to be seconded to the Treasury Department. We have the full...
我們有財政部的公文要求協助
Barry? Who is consistently the best shot of this class?
這班上誰的射擊成績最好
Williamson and Stone. Call them out, one at a time.
威廉森和斯通 好 替我叫他們來好嗎 一次一位
Are either of the men married? No.
請問他們是否結婚了? 沒有
Good. Williamson!
威廉森
You're married. I don't want any married men.
你可是結過婚了 我不要結過婚的人
All right, stand easy, son. I want to ask you something.
好了 稍息 小夥子 我有些話問你
Why do you want to join the force? To protect and...
你為何投考警校 為了保護
To protect and serve... To protect and...
為了保護…服務
Please don't search for the yearbook answer. Just tell me what you think.
別背書上的答案 告訴我你的想法
What I think? I... You...
我的想法 我
...could help...the force.
…可以幫助…警方
You can help... With the force.
你可以幫助
Thank you. There goes the next Chief of Police.
好了 謝謝 未來的局長人選
At ease!
稍息
Stone! Out here.
斯通 出來
This kid's a prodigy.
這小子是天才
Why do you want to join the force? To protect the property and...
你為何加入員警行列 為了保護人民財產
Oh, please, don't waste my time with that bullshit.
請別說廢話 浪費我的時間
Where are you from, Stone?
你是哪裡人? 斯通
From the Southside. Stone?
南方人
George Stone, that's your name?
斯通 喬治.斯通是你本名嗎?
What's your real name? That is my real name.
你的真名是什麼 那就是我的真名
Nah! What was it before you changed it?
不是 在你改名換姓前叫什麼?
Giuseppe Petri. Geez, I knew it!
喬瑟比班達 我就知道
That's all you need, one thieving wop on the team!
我早就說過隊上有壞分子
What's that you said?
你說什麼
I said that you're a lying member of a no-good race.
我說你撒謊 是個敗類
That's much better than you, you stinking Irish pig.
比你好多了 你這愛爾蘭臭豬
Oh, I like him.
我喜歡他
Yeah, I like him, too.
我也喜歡他
You just joined the Treasury Department, son.
你剛加入了財政部小夥子
Yeah, okay.
好吧
Eliot Ness.
艾略特.奈斯
With reports from stake-outs on the North and West side, and...
我們從西區和北區接獲報告
Thank you, Lieutenant. Thank you.
謝謝 警官 謝謝
What do you think?
你覺得如何
I think there's nothing like vaudeville.
像雜耍團的小丑一樣
That's what I think. Now, are you ready to go to work?
我也是這樣想 現在 你們準備好去辦事了嗎?
Where are we going? On a liquor raid.
去哪裡
We need another man.
去突檢私酒 我們還少個人
Mr Ness? This is very interesting.
奈斯先生 這很有趣
I've found a financial disbursement pattern which shows some irregu...
我發現財政部的紀錄上
You carry a badge? Yes.
你有警證嗎?
Carry a gun.
拿支槍吧
Jimmy...? What?
吉米 什麼?
What the hell are you dressed for? Hallowe'en?
你穿那樣是幹什麼? 萬聖節嗎
Shut up. I'm working.
閉嘴 我在上班
Where? The circus?
哪兒? 馬戲團嗎
Well, here we are. What are we doing here?
就是這裡 我們來這裡幹什麼
Liquor raid.
突檢私酒
Here? !
這裡?
Everybody knows where the booze is. The problem isn't finding it.
奈斯先生 大家都知道私酒在何處
The problem is who wants to cross Capone. Let's go.
問題不在於找出私酒 而在於誰敢招惹卡彭 我們進去
You'd better be damn sure, Malone.
你最好確定是這裡
If you walk through this door, you're walking into a world of trouble.
一進入此門你就是走進麻煩之中
There's no turning back. Do you understand?
不能回頭 你明白嗎
Yes, I do.
是的 我明白
Good. Give me that axe.
好 把斧頭給我
Federal officers! Get your hands in the air!
聯邦官員 手舉起來
Nobody moves! This is a raid!
不准動 突擊檢查
Everybody... What are you doing here?
你們是在幹什麼
All this stuff is impounded! You're all under arrest!
所有的物品都充公 你們全被捕了
Hey! This isn't right! Hey! This is no good!
這樣不對
You got a warrant? Sure! Here's my warrant.
你們可有拘捕令 這就是拘票
How do you think he feels now? Better...or worse?
你們現在認為他感覺好些還是不好?
What is that? What is that?
那是什麼?
Yes, what is it? God, I'm with a heathen.
那是什麼? 你不信教嗎
That is my callbox key. And that is Saint Jude.
那是我的鑰匙鏈 那個是聖猶大
Il Santo Jude. He's the patron saint of lost causes.
猶大是失敗者的守護神
And policemen.
他也守護員警
Patron saint of policemen? Everybody needs a friend.
員警的守護神 每個人都需要朋友的
Lost causes, policemen...
失敗和員警
Which do you want to be? I want to be a cop.
你想當哪一種 我想當員警
You do? Yes.
是嗎? 是的
Why?
為什麼?
'T o protect the property and the citizenry...'
為了保護市民生命財產
Whoa, it's all right.
沒事的 沒事的
What? ! I got to tell you, congratulations!
你幹嘛? 我只是來恭賀你們
It's okay if I get a picture of you and your men?
我可以替你們拍張照嗎
Yeah. But not for publication. Just for us!
好 但不能發表 只能給我們
Anything you say, Mr Ness.
聽你的 奈斯先生
Closer in... Oh, that's great. Okay, ready? Hold it.
看這裡 好了 預備
Life goes on.
日子要過下去
A man becomes preeminent, he's expected to have enthusiasms.
人們期望卓越的人有熱忱
Enthusiasms...
熱忱
What are mine?
我呢?
What draws my admiration? What is that which gives me joy?
我熱衷什麼 什麼能使我高興?
Dames! Boozing
美女…喝酒
Baseball!
棒球
A man...
一個人
A man stands alone at the plate.
一個人上場打球時
This is the time for what?
那是什麼時刻
For individual achievement.
一個人的成就時刻
There he stands alone.
他單獨站在那
But in the field, what?
在場上有些什麼?
Part of a team.
球隊的一部分
Teamwork...
團隊合作
Looks, throws, catches, hustles. Part of one big team.
投球 接球 打暗號構成一個球隊
Bats himself the live-long day, Babe Ruth, Ty Cobb, and so on.
打拼出自己的人生 盧斯、庫伯（棒球選手）都是如此
If his team don't field...what is he?
如果球隊沒勝出 那算什麼
You follow me?
你們懂我意思嗎
No one.
什麼都不算
Sunny day, the stands are full of fans. What does he have to say?
現在天氣晴朗 看臺上全是人
他有什麼話說
I'm going out there for myself.
我上場是為了我自己
But...I get nowhere unless the team wins.
但是除非球隊贏球我才有功勞
'Now I lay me down to sleep'
在我睡覺的時候
'I pray the Lord my soul to keep'
我祈天主佑我靈
'lf I should die before I wake'
當我清醒的時候
'I pray the Lord my soul to take'
我祈天主護我靈
Amen. God bless...
阿門
God bless Mommy, God bless Annie, God bless Daddy. Amen.
上帝保佑媽媽 保佑爸爸 保佑洋娃娃 阿門
Amen.
阿門
Good night, Daddy. Good night, little girl.
晚安 爸爸 晚安 小姑娘
Want to rub Eskimo? Butterfly?
要擦鼻子嗎
Where are you going? What?
你上哪去?
Where are you going?
你要到哪去?
I thought I'd go downstairs, some work to do for tomorrow.
我要下樓去準備明天的工作
You had a full day today, though? Yes, I certainly did.
你忙了一天了 是嗎 是的 沒錯
And you've still got some energy left?
你還有剩餘精力嗎
Oh, a lot of work.
工作真多
Well, why don't you come up and brush my hair? You 'Detective'
你何不上來替我梳梳頭
“緝酒戰士終於得勝”
How are we doing Capone's organisation is diverse.
進展如何 卡彭的組織真是複雜
It owns Canadian Holding Company Associations, which owns in turn
你看 他們有加拿大控股公司
Green Light Laundry, Midwest Cabs, Jolly Time Playthings...
旗下又有洗衣店、車廠、玩具公司…
Jolly Time Playthings? Yes.
玩具公司? 是的
Remind me to get a present for my daughter.
記得提醒我買玩具
...Bahama Ship-to-Shore, Miss Lucy Togs...the list is endless!
巴拿馬船運公司 說也說不完
And all the business is legitimate, and none is owned by Al Capone.
全都在他人名下 沒有一家是登記于卡彭名下的
But we can get him on income tax evasion if we can show
我們無法因他未報稅而告他
that any of the 'organisation' business money is going to him.
除非我們能證明 這些公司的錢都流向他那裡
Legally, he receives no income. He doesn't receive anything?
在法律上 他沒得利益 他沒有任何收入?
Mr Ness? You have a visitor. Mister Ness!
奈斯先生 有訪客 奈斯先生
Could we talk for a minute? I'm John O'Shea, Alderman...
我能和你談談嗎? 地檢處的奧立佛
Yes, I know who you are.
我知道你是誰
Would you excuse us?
請你們出去一下
We are busy with several large operations. What can I do for you?
我們的工作正忙 請問有何貴幹?
I came up to congratulate you on a job well done.
我是來恭賀你們完成了件大功
Share your good fortune on such a lovely day.
來分享你們的一些好運
What's that?
那是什麼?
What is that? Mr Ness, you're an educated man.
那是什麼? 奈斯先生你是個受過教育的人
Let me pay you the compliment of being blunt.
我非常敬佩你
There is a large and popular business which you are causing dismay.
有一件很大很熱門的生意 受到了你們的干擾
Why don't you just cross the street and let things take their course?
你何不睜隻眼閉隻眼聽其自然
Would you come in here, please?
你們進來
In Roman times, when a fellow tried to bribe a public official,
在羅馬時代 如果有人被判行賄官員
they would cut off his nose, sew him in a bag
他會被割掉鼻子
with a wild animal, and throw that bag in the river.
和一隻野獸裝入同一袋中 再被丟入河中
You tell your master that we must agree to...disagree!
你去告訴你的主子 我們一致同意反對你們
You're making a mistake. I'm beginning to enjoy my mistakes.
你犯了大錯 我已經犯錯了 我正開始樂在其中
You fellows are 'untouchable' is that it? No one can get to you?
你們鐵面無私 是不是 沒人能動你們?
You tell Capone... that I'll see him in hell.
去告訴卡彭 我會送他下地獄
Hey! Nice house!
嘿 好房子
I said, nice house! Do you live there?
我說 好一座房子 你住在那裡嗎
Little girl's having a birthday, huh?
小女孩要過生日是嗎?
Yes.
是的
Nice to have a family.
有個家真好
Yes, it is.
沒錯
A man should take care, see that nothing happens to them.
你要好好照顧 免得出了什麼事
Catherine? !
凱瑟林
Catherine!
Where's the baby? She's upstairs. Eliot!
孩子呢 她在樓上 艾略特
What were you doing up? I had to finish my ironing.
你在幹什麼 我在熨衣服
You did? You're gonna come with Daddy now, okay?
是嗎 跟爸爸來好嗎
Eliot? Okay, it's all right!
艾略特
Okay, let's go.
我們走
Stay there! Keep your eye on the street!
留在那裡 注意街上
Where's Malone? On the stake-out. He'll be here.
馬龍呢? 他在監視嫌疑犯 馬上就到
Who's this guy? He's on Malone's list. He's okay.
他是誰 他是我們的人 沒問題的
Drive to the station. She'll let you know where to go when you get there.
好吧 送他們到車站 到了後告訴我一聲
Take off your hat.
是的 長官 帽子脫下來
Anything happens, shoot first. You understand me?
發生什麼事就先開槍 明白嗎?
Yes, Mr Ness.
是的 奈斯先生
Eskimo and butterfly, Dad. Okay.
擦擦鼻子 爸爸
Now, go!
走吧
Malone!
馬龍
Are they okay? Yeah.
你沒事吧
You sure the cop's okay? He'd better be, he's my cousin.
很好 那個員警沒問題吧 應該沒問題 他是我表弟
I want to hurt the man, Malone! You hear me? !
我要抓那個人 馬龍你聽到了嗎?
I want to take the battle to him. I want to hurt Capone.
我要開始戰鬥 我要打擊卡彭
Well, then, a Merry Christmas, we've got some great news.
那麼聖誕快樂 因為我有個好消息
A huge international shipment's coming.
將有大批私貨運來
We've got the time, the place and the whole shebang.
我們知道時間、地點以及整個作業
Well, what are we doing standing here, then?
那我們還等什麼
How do you come by this information?
你哪裡來的消息
That's the second rule of police work:
那是員警工作的第二課
if you want to keep a secret, don't tell the boss.
如果你想保守秘密 就別告訴頭兒
You know he's making over $3 million a year?
他每年黑的錢超過三百萬元
But he's paid no taxes, nothing's in his name.
但他沒交稅 因為不是以他的名義
If we can establish any payments to him,
如果我們能確認他收到任何一筆錢
we can prosecute him for income tax evasion.
我們就可告他逃稅
What?
什麼?
I said, we can prosecute him for income tax evasion!
我說我們可告他逃稅
Try a murderer for not paying his taxes? !
以逃稅罪名控告殺人兇手
Well, it's better than nothing.
好過沒有
All right. How do we link him to the money?
好吧 要怎麼做到
I don't know.
我不知道
Go to sleep, Oscar.
去睡覺吧
A convoy of 5-10 trucks with good Canadian whiskey
有五到十輛卡車滿載加拿大威士卡
will be met by a high-level member of the Capone organisation.
由卡彭組織中的好手交易
He will be bringing full payment for the shipment in cash.
他攜帶現金當場交易
Now, the meet is to take place just over the border on the American side.
交易地點在邊界 美國這一邊
We want to confiscate the liquor and the cash.
我們的目標是沒收私酒和現款
Captain? We will await their signal.
隊長 我們會等他們的信號
When they're on the road and have given the signal,
當他們上路後信號發出
we will engage from the Canadian side of the bridge.
我們將由加拿大那邊攻擊橋那一端
Thus taking them by surprise from the rear.
出其不意攻擊他們背後
And surprise, as you very well know, Mr Ness, is half the battle.
奈斯先生 突擊就已贏得了一半的勝利
Surprise is half the battle. Many things are half the battle.
突擊只贏了一半 很多事只是一半還不夠
Losing is half the battle. Let's think about what is all the battle.
還有一半機會會輸 我們要贏得全部
Let's take the fight to them, gentlemen!
各位 向他們開戰吧
Thank you, Captain.
謝謝你 隊長
All right! Move out!
好 出發
Take it easy.
別緊張
Take it easy! lt'll all happen in time.
別緊張 船到橋頭自然直
This is the job.
這就是工作
Don't wait for it to happen, don't even want it to happen.
別期待它發生 不希望它發生
Just watch what does happen.
只是等著看發生了什麼事
Are you my 'tutor'?
你是我的導師?
Yes, sir, that I am.
是的 我是的
Did you check it already? Yes, I did.
你檢查過了嗎 是的
Then leave it alone.
那就別再碰了
You're a good cop, Giuseppe.
你是個好員警
You're doing good. You're gonna do just fine.
你很不錯 你會幹得很好的
Wallace, are you cold? Yes, I am, a little.
華萊士你冷嗎 有一點
Then stamp your feet. It'll keep you warm.
不斷的跺腳 會使你暖和
You learn something, 20 years walking the beat.
那是我20年巡夜的經驗
Stitches and standing in the rain...
站在風雪、大雨中學來的
Listen, Mr Ness...
聽我說 奈斯先生
I had an idea.
我有個主意
You all have your spare shells?
你們都帶好彈藥了
If you have to fire, hold low and squeeze.
如果要開槍的話 臥倒 不要留情
And put your man down.
把對手幹掉
Because he'll do the same to you.
因為他們也想要你的命
Shoot to kill.
槍槍致命
Did you hear what I said? Yes, I did. Shoot to kill.
聽到了嗎 是的 聽到了 槍槍致命
Let's go.
出發
Easy...
放鬆
The Canadians will not show until I flash the badge.
加拿大人在我發出信號前不會出現
So we must cover the ground to the bridge as quickly as possible.
所以我們要儘快沖到橋上
George, the count's right.
喬治 看來沒錯 數目正確
I'm concerned about the size of these barrels!
我擔心的不是數目我擔心的是酒桶的大小
Malone, you and I will take the men...
馬龍 我們倆
Move it! Move it, Georgie!
加拿大騎警…喬治
Get over here! Leave the stuff in the cars!
快走 把貨留下!
Charge!
沖啊!
What the hell! You got to die of something
管他的 人總免不了一死
Look! Here they come! Mounties! Let's get out of here!
他們來了…離開這兒
Move, move!
快 快!
I can't believe it!
真不敢相信
Here are the codes. Give me that.
帳本 給我
Don't let those cars off the bridge!
別讓車子下橋
Stone, take the first car!
斯通 攔住第一輛車 收到
Get this shit out of the way!
快走
Tough guy!
混球!
Stone!
斯通
I'm okay.
我沒事
You thugs!
兇手們!
You all right?
你沒事吧?
Yeah. There he is! Go get him!
是的 他在那裡 去抓他
All right! Enough of this running shit!
好了 別再跑了
Well, Georgie-boy! Well, what have we got here?
喬治小子 這是什麼
Hello.
問你呢
All right! Drop the gun!
好了 把槍丟下
Put your hands in the air, you're under arrest.
把手舉起來 你被捕了
I said, drop it!
我說了 槍丟下
God, didn't ya hear what I said? !
你沒聽見我的話嗎
What are you, deaf? !
你是聾子嗎
What is this, a game? !
這只是遊戲嗎
Here. Sit down.
坐下
Stone's gonna be all right.
斯通不要緊
I got the fellow with the satchel.
我抓到拿手提袋的人
I had to kill him. Oh, yeah.
我不得不殺他
He's as dead as Julius Caesar.
對 他死的像愷撒 (愷撒遇刺時自以為刀槍不入)
Would you rather it was you? No, I would not.
你希望死的是你嗎 不 我才不要
Well, then you've done your duty. Go home and sleep well tonight.
那你已經盡到責任了 今晚可回去好好睡覺
The things you see when you're out without your gun.
你已失去了你的保護
Now you're a long way from the Southside, George.
你現在離南區遠得很 喬治
I'm talking to you. Did you come here to open a shooting gallery?
我在和你說話 你是來此開戰的嗎?
I want you to write down the names of your superiors and contacts.
我要你寫出你老闆和你連絡人的姓名
Why don't you kiss my ass?
你去吻我的臭屁吧
Perhaps you didn't hear me. Eliot?
也許你沒聽懂 艾略特
You've broken the law... Eliot!
你射擊聯邦官員違反禁酒令
You can be tough in Leavenworth for 30 years.
你可能會被關上三十年
You're going inside for all day! Is that what you want?
你可以在裡面待上一輩子 你喜歡那樣嗎
Eliot! What? !
什麼事?
Look at this!
看這個
Look at this! What is this?
你看 那是什麼?
What is this?
那是什麼?
You got a lot of money changing hands in this book.
你這帳本上有許多錢轉出
What is this, 'war'? And 'police precincts'
這是什麼意思 “戰爭”“員警分局”?
And you got a heading here... 'Circuit Court'
還有這個“巡迴法庭”是什麼意思
You got a heading here, 'Circuit Court' What is this?
“巡迴法庭”是什麼意思
Nothing There's nothing you can make out of it.
沒什麼 你不會明白的
If any of these coded entries indicate payment to Capone,
如果我們能證明這些錢是付給卡彭的話
then we can put Capone away.
我們就能將卡彭繩之以法
Which entry is Al Capone? A. Costa, is that his code name?
告訴我們 哪一些錢是付給卡彭的? A是卡彭的代號嗎?
You'll do the whole thing in the joint unless you help us.
除非你幫助我們不然你會坐一輩子牢
Translate this ledger for us!
我要你將這些代號翻譯出來
In hell. In hell? !
去你的 去你的?
You will hang high unless you cooperate.
除非你合作不然你會被高高的吊死
This man can finger Al Capone, put him behind bars.
這個人可指證卡彭 使卡彭入獄
Why don't you guys just fuck off? !
你們去死吧
I'm not fucking with you! We'll have that information one way or another.
我懶得跟你說了 我們總有方法問出來的
Not that way. Out. You're gonna talk!
你會說的
You're gonna be begging to talk!
你會求我讓你招供
You dirty son-of-a-bitch! Enough out of you.
你這個下流胚子 別這樣
Hey, come on, you, on your feet!
起來 你 站起來
I need you to help me to translate this book!
我要你替我譯這本帳簿
I'm not gonna ask you a second time.
我不會問你第二次
I'm gonna count to three.
我只數到三
What's the matter? Can't you talk with a gun in your mouth?
怎麼了? 嘴裡有支槍就說不出話了?
One.
一
Two!
二
Three.
三
I'm gonna talk!
好 我願意說
Don't ! I'm gonna tell ya whatever ya want. What do ya want to know?
不 我什麼都招 你們要知道什麼
Now, don't let him clean himself until after he talks.
他說完後 才讓他清潔
Now, ask him what you want to know.
現在想知道什麼就問他吧
All right... Okay, I want to know the name of the bookkeeper.
好了 我要知道記帳員的姓名
I want a complete translation of the code. I want a complete...
我要你將代號全譯出來 我要完全的
Mister Ness!
奈斯先生
I do not approve of your methods!
我不贊成你的做法
Yeah? Well, you're not from Chicago.
是嗎? 你不是從芝加哥來的
What? They got the shipment.
什麼? 他們把貨沒收了
What? ! They got the whole shipment.
什麼? 他們把所有的貨都沒收了
I want that son-of-a-bitch dead! We're trying to locate...
我要那個混蛋沒命 我要他死
What am I, alone in this world? Did I ask you what you're trying to do?
搞什麼? 我問過你打算做什麼嗎
I want you to get this fuck where he breathes! I want Eliot Ness dead!
我要你除掉他的人 我要你找出他的住處 我要他死
I want his family dead, his house burnt to the ground!
我要他全家死光 我要在他的骨灰上撒尿
I want to piss on his ashes!
我要他知道厲害
Look at this guy, this guy, he's so serious.
看看他 這小傢伙 他好嚴肅
Well, he's got a lot on his mind. He does?
他腦子裡在想很多事 是嗎
Yes. Like what?
是的 像什麼
Like what his name is.
想他叫什麼名字
John, I thought that was all settled. I thought we liked John.
約翰 不是說好了嗎? 約翰 我們都喜歡這名字
I suppose his middle name will be Law.
奈斯 他該叫朗恩
No...it'll be Edgar.
不 叫艾得格
It'll be J. Edgar... I don't think so.
叫J.艾得格 我覺得不好
God, you're beautiful.
老天 你真美
You should have seen us last night.
你昨晚來看我們會更美
I know. I should have been here. I wanted to be here.
我知道 我該來 我想來
I know. I understand, I do.
我知道 我瞭解 真的
Just tell me, are you being careful?
只要你小心就好
Careful as mice. Are you making progress?
我小心得像老鼠一樣 有進展嗎
Progress? Yes?
進展?
Mrs Ness, I think your husband just became the man who got Al Capone.
奈斯太太 我想你先生逮到卡彭了
Gentlemen! A subpoena was issued for Alphonse Capone
先生們 今天上午地檢處
by my office this morning, for the crime of evading
控告卡彭先生
and conspiring to evade Federal Income Tax.
罪名是漏稅及圖謀逃稅
What's the maximum he could get? If convicted on all counts,
卡彭先生會判刑多久? 如果所有罪名成立
Mr Capone could have up to 28 years.
卡彭可判二十八年
Excuse me, that's all. Thank you.
失陪了
The car's in the yard. When ya get him there, don't answer the phone.
車子在巷子裡 到了之後 別接電話
We'll call, let it ring... Twice.
我們來時 讓鈴聲… 響二次
We'll call... From the corner.
我們會打電話… 在拐角處
Anybody knocks on the door... Come out shooting. I got it.
有人敲門的話就… 開槍射擊 我都知道
You enjoy the tactical aspects of law enforcement, Oscar?
看來你很喜歡執法的工作
Much more diverting than accounting.
是 比當會計有趣多了
I'm being good to you, you got to be good to me.
我對你們好 你們也要回報我
We made a deal, we're gonna stick to it, okay?
我們有協議 我們會遵守的 好嗎?
Oh, yes, much more diverting than accounting.
對的 比當會計有意思多了
Okay, we see yous tonight.
好 晚上見
All right, all the way down and no stops.
好了 一直下去中間不停
...he's been saying, "I will speak up."
他能說:我會大聲地說
For which I must commend the excellent work
我得讚揚艾略特.奈斯
of Eliot Ness and his squad of Untouchables.
和他隊伍的出色表現
What was it, a boy or a girl? Boy.
恭喜 是男孩還是女孩? 男孩
Congratulations! What's his name? John.
恭喜 叫什麼名字 約翰
John? Yeah. John James.
約翰 是的 約翰.詹姆斯
So she's okay? Yeah, she's okay.
她好吧 她很好
In fact, when she gets out, she wants to repaint the house.
她說她出院後要油漆房子
Then she'll find the house too small, you'll have to move.
再下來她會嫌房子小你就必須搬家
Goodness, it's nice to be married. If you can stand the pain.
結婚真不錯 如果你能忍受痛苦的話
Mr Burns, where's Mr Wallace?
伯恩先生 華萊士呢?
Didn't you see him? He just went down in the service elevator.
你見到他們嗎? 他剛從貨物電梯下去
You keep an eye out at all times... Take it easy, we'll be fine.
必須隨時警戒 我瞭解他們 別緊張
Did he say the service elevator? Yes.
他是說搭貨物電梯? 是的
Wallace! Wallace! Here, let's take the stairs.
華萊士華萊士走樓梯
No, no! Easy... Easy!
不 別衝動 別衝動
Oscar.
“動搖”
Oh, Jesus.
天啊
You gonna be all right?
你沒事吧
It's always a crime when a young guy goes down in the line, Jimmy.
看到自己人躺在那裡 心裡實在很難過
I'd hate to see it happen to someone I know.
我恨見到這事發生在我認識的人身上
Sometimes it's better not to get involved.
有時候 置身事外最明智
Jimmy! Take a day off. Get out of the city for a while.
吉米 請一天假離開市區
You know what I mean?
懂我意思吧?
Al Capone. We have no Mr Capone...
艾爾卡彭 我們這裡沒有卡彭先生
I know, get him. We have no Mr Capone...
叫他 叫他 我們這裡沒有卡彭先生
I said...
我說了…
Something you want here? My friend was killed today.
你有事嗎 我的朋友今天被殺了
I don't care. You don't care.
幹我屁事 不幹你的事?
Now he does.
現在有關了
Come on here, Capone. You want to fight? You and me, right here?
來吧 卡彭 你要打嗎 你要打嗎? 你和我就在這裡
That's it, come on!
怎麼了 來呀
You afraid to come out from behind your men, to stand up for yourself?
別躲在爪牙背後不敢自己站出來?
You want to do the mat now? Yeah! Come on, you son-of-a-bitch!
你想現在幹是不是 你要現在來嗎? 來呀 你這狗娘養的
What? Easy.
什麼? 冷靜
You talk to me like that in front of my son? Fuck you and your family!
你在我手下面前那樣罵我 幹他媽的你和你家人
Easy. It's me. It's me!
是我 是我
Not this way.
這樣不行
You fuck, you got nothing You're nothing but talk and a badge.
你什麼都沒有 我知道
You're here because you got nothing in court, no bookkeeper, nothing
你來此是因為你沒有證據 你沒有證物 沒有簿記員
If you were a man, you would've done it now! You got nothing you punk!
你要是男子漢的話就現在來幹 你一無所有 混球
Well, no, I understand.
不 我…我瞭解
Believe me, I understand.
相信我 我瞭解
Well, what's happened?
怎麼回事?
He says he can't be unprotected.
他說他不能沒有證據
What is it that the guy says?
他究竟怎麼說的
He says he won't make a fool out of himself,
他說他不願意讓自己出醜
and he won't go into court without a witness.
沒有證人 所以他要撤回他的控訴
So tomorrow morning the D.A. will announce that he's dropping the case.
所以，明天早上，D.A.將宣佈他的案子情況
He's gonna give up. He won't do it without a witness.
他要放棄 沒有證人他不願開庭
We have Wallace's files and the ledgers.
我們有華萊士的檔案和那帳本
There's a time when I think you have to cut your losses.
有時候你得承認失敗
Hello?
喂
Hello.
Yes.
是的
No, he didn't have a family.
他沒有家人
How is everything there?
情形如何?
No, you do it however you want.
不 你看著辦就行了
I promise I will.
我保證我會的
You give her my love.
代我問候他
I love you, too.
我也愛你
Mr Ness, we got a ledger here listing payments to Chicago City officials.
奈斯先生 這本帳本有費用支出牽涉芝加哥政府官員
We got Al Capone, Frank Nitti... I think that's enough for today.
也有卡彭那批人…今天到此為止 明天再說吧
If we don't stay on top... That'll do. Thank you.
斯通 就這樣了 謝謝
I'd like to request to stick around.
我要求留下來
We got to bust these guys. I know we got to.
我們要逮住那些人 我知道
Is that it?
就此結束了嗎?
I'm sorry? You heard me.
你說什麼? 你聽見我的話了
My question is, are we done?
我在問 我們就此結束嗎
Yes, I think we're done.
是的 我想是的
So we sat in at a game that was above our head?
你是說我們是輸的一方
It appears so. It appears so to Mr Wallace.
似乎是如此 對華萊士來說的確是這樣
He's dead! And the D.A. is gonna drop the case!
他死了 檢察官要撤銷案子
He will not go into court without a witness
沒有證人他不願起訴
and without Capone's bookkeeper, Walter Payne.
沒有卡彭的簿記員他不願起訴的
What are you prepared to do now? What would you have me do?
那你現在打算怎麼辦 你希望我怎麼做
I have taken this as far as it can go.
我已盡力了
What did your wife want? She wanted to know if I was...
你太太要幹什麼? 她要知道我是否…
My wife? Yeah.
我太太? 對
She wanted to know if I was all right.
她想知道事情是否順利
It's nice being married, eh?
結婚真不錯吧
Yes.
是啊
She's sitting in some room surrounded by people she doesn't know,
她在那裡由一群陌生人保護著
going over... kitchen colour charts or something.
只能在想廚房該漆什麼顏色
Some part of the world still cares what colour the kitchen is.
誰在乎廚房該漆什麼色
Eliot, I want you to do one more thing for me.
艾略特 我要你再為我做一件事
Get back to the D.A. and stall him.
去檢察官那裡拖延這案子
Wait a minute, stall him with what? Just do as I say.
等一下 怎麼個拖延 照我的話去做就是了
I think I know how to find this guy.
我知道怎麼找出那傢伙
“卡彭簿記員被傳喚”
Walter?
沃爾特
Al says we got to get out of town until he can fix this subpoena thing.
艾爾說要我們到外地去避避風頭
We're leaving tonight.
我們今晚動身
Two ball, down.
兩球入袋
Mike, you got a minute?
邁克 你有空嗎
I do now, don't I?
現在有了
And what are you doing in a club for cops, Jimmy?
你到員警俱樂部幹嘛
This is a place for cops.
這裡只有員警能來
Can we step outside?
到外面去談如何
All right, all right, but I got nothing to say to ya.
好…但我和你無話可說
Where the hell are we going, for a swim? Get out of the rain, you fool.
你要去哪裡? 游泳嗎 外面在下雨 笨蛋
What? What? !
什麼事?
I just need one more piece of information.
我想再要一件情報
One more? Jimmy!
再一件 吉米
I just risked my life for ya. I need to find that bookkeeper.
我已為你冒了生命危險 我需要找出那個簿記員
Are you crazy? Y ou're crazy. I warned you to get out of town.
你瘋了! 你是瘋了 我曾警告你要離開
If they knew it was me, I'm dead. I need to find that bookkeeper.
如果他們知道是我的話我就死定了 我必須找到那簿記員
You're fucking nuts, man! You're out of your fucking mind!
你簡直就瘋了 你瘋了
And I tried to save your life.
我還想救你的命
Get your hands off. You owe me, Jimmy, I don't owe you nothing
把手拿開 你欠我 吉米 我可什麼也不欠你
My people are being killed. We're your people!
我的人被殺了 你的人 我們才是同志
You? ! You fucking run with the dagos! They've ruined this town.
你是我的同志? 是的 你和他們同流合污使得這城市敗壞
For ten years I can't say that I'm a cop for the shit that's going on!
十年來 我無法抬頭挺胸以當員警為傲
Ah, bullshit! Fucking bullshit! Look at yourself! Look at yourself!
狗屎 一派胡言 看看你 看看你自己
Go on and live the charade, with your soft clothes and federal stooges.
去做你的英雄夢吧 穿著便衣和聯邦專員辦案
What do you think he's gonna do? Keep your mouth off that!
你想他還能怎麼辦 他是想清理這城市
I need to know where this guy is, and I need to know now!
我要知道那簿記員在哪裡 我現在就要知道
I'm gonna rat you out for all the shit that I know that you've done!
否則我要把你這輩子 幹的醜事全揭出來
I'm gonna turn you over!
我要告發你
This is a dead man talking to me. Is it?
你不想活了 是嗎?
You're dead.
你死定了
Who the hell do ya think ya are?
你以為你是誰
I'll have your ass hanging from the flagpole in the morning
我現在就宰掉你
Let's cut the woofing, pal. You tell me,
少說狠話了
or you're going to hospital or the fucking morgue!
你想進醫院還是墳場
You're gonna fight it out and we'll have a case.
要怎麼拖延? 我根本無法成立此案
Yes? On what basis? I'm not gonna make a fool...
有何依據? 我不打算起訴 我可不想鬧笑話
Don't tell me about making a fool out of yourself.
別說你會鬧笑話
I have men out there risking more than that.
我的人正在外面冒生命危險
We have a lead, and we are following that lead
我們有線索 我們正循線索去追查
at risk to more than our standing. So don't you dare stop now.
你現在絕不能放棄
Yeah, Stone. Give me Ness.
是的 斯通 奈斯呢?
He's at the D.A. 's.
他在檢察官的辦公室
Tell him I know where Payne is and to meet me at my place.
告訴他我知道佩恩下落 叫他馬上到我這裡來
Al! Al! Mr Capone!
艾爾.卡彭先生
What about that court case? I'm gonna tell ya something
出庭的事如何 我告訴你們
Somebody messes with me, I'm gonna mess with him.
誰和我搗蛋我就要他好看
Somebody steals from me, I'm gonna say 'you stole'
有人偷我東西 我就罵他是小偷
not talk to him for spitting on the sidewalk.
我不會理會這種人
You understand?
你們明白嗎
Now, I have done nothing to hurt these people.
我沒有傷害那些人
But they're angered at me. So what do they do?
但他們生我的氣 所以他們如何做?
Doctor up some income tax, for which they got no case, to annoy me.
他們便扯出交稅問題 他們根本沒證據 好使我惱怒
To speak to me like men? No.
他們像男子漢嗎? 不是
To harass a peaceful man.
竟要逮捕一位講和平的人
I pray to God that if I ever have a grievance,
我向上帝祈禱 可以的話
I would have just a little more self respect.
我只要求些自尊
I'll tell you one more thing. In an all-out prize fight,
我再告訴你們一件事 一場戰鬥要等到戰鬥結束後
when one guy's left standing, that's how you know who won.
只剩一個人站著 那時才知道誰是贏家
“拉辛路”
“拉辛路 1634號”
Isn't that just like a wop?
真是不知好歹
Brings a knife to a gun fight.
用刀來對付槍
Get out of here, ya dago bastard!
滾出去 你這混蛋
Go on, get your ass out of here!
快點 快滾
Shots! Shots! I heard shots!
槍聲 我聽到槍聲
Stay back, everybody stay back, right now.
退後 大家退後 快
Round the back.
繞到後面
Malone!
馬龍
Malone.
Goddamn! Stone!
天 斯通…斯通
Stone!
斯通
The phone!
電話
Oh, God. Call an ambulance!
叫救護車
This is Stone, Treasury Department, 1634 Racine, we need an ambulance.
我是斯通 財政部的 派救護車至拉辛路1634號
What? 1634 Racine!
什麼?
This? You want this?
你要這個
You want this?
What?
什麼?
Bookkeeper. What?
簿記員
Book... The bookkeeper?
那個簿記員? 簿記員
Bookkeeper! The bookkeeper? What?
簿記員？什麼？
The bookkeeper, he's on this train? Yes.
簿記員 他搭這班火車
He's on this train.
他搭這班火車?
Now! What are you prepared to do? !
你打算怎麼辦
Stay. Stay.
撐著
Stay! Malone...
馬龍!
No. No, no!
不
Not this... Not this man...
不 不是這個
Traings leaving for Miami 12.05, Mr Ness.
到邁阿密的火車十二時五分開出
We'll be there.
我們會趕到的
The bookkeeper's no good to us dead.
死的簿記員對我們沒用 斯通
Stone? Yes, sir.
是的 先生
“通往各班列車”
Cover the south entrance.
監視南邊入口
We're almost home. We're almost home.
我們快回到家了
Your attention, please. The Miami Flier departs at 12.05 from 33.
往邁阿密的特快車 將於12點5分在33號月臺開出
All aboard.
乘客請儘快上車
Stay right there. Stay right there.
你等一下
Stay right there. Stay right there, honey.
Your attention, please. The Miami Flier, leaving at 12.05,
往邁阿密的特快車 將於12點5分
now boarding on track 33. All aboard!
在33號月臺開出 請乘客儘快上車
Just here. I'm just gonna leave this right here.
就這樣停下來
Your attention, please. The Miami Flier, leaving at 12.05,
請注意 往邁阿密的特快車 將於12點5分
is now boarding on track 33. All aboard!
在33號月臺開出 請乘客儘快上車
One more. Here we go.
再來一次
Here we go. You ready?
來了 準備好嗎
I'm right here, honey. Here we go.
我在這裡 好嗎
Your attention, please. May I have your attention, please?
請各位乘客注意
This is the final call for the Miami Flier,
往邁阿密的特快車最後召集
leaving at 12.05 on track 33. All aboard!
將於12點5分在33號月臺開出 請乘客儘快上車
Here, let me. Get your bags. Oh, thank you so much. Thank you.
我來幫你 真多謝你
Are you all right? Thank you.
謝謝你 先生
You're such a gentleman. It's so kind of you to help me.
你真好心 肯幫助我
I really wasn't sure if we'd make it or not.
我擔心自己是否能辦到
Is there some problem I can help you with?
有問題嗎? 我來幫你 不用
No. I really can't thank you enough.
我真的很感謝你
Isn't this fun? You're being such a good boy, sweetheart.
你真可愛
Thank you again, this is so wonderful.Thank you, sir.
你真好 真謝謝你
Please, let me take it from here. You've been such a great help.
我來吧 先生 謝謝你幫忙
Thank you so much. We're almost there.
謝謝 我們快到了
I'll take it from here, sir. Thank you very much for your help.
謝謝你的幫忙
Don't cry, sweetheart. We're almost home.
別哭 寶寶 我們快到家了
Is something wrong? Sir?
有什麼不對嗎? 先生
Come on! Come on, let's get out of here.
快點! 離開這裡
What are you doing Shut up!
你幹什麼? 閉嘴 走
What are you doing Shut the fuck up!
閉嘴
Hold it! Please...
別動
My baby! Stay there. He's all right.
我的寶寶 別動 他沒事
I said hold it!
我說別動
I'm walking out with the bookkeeper.
我要和簿記員一起走出去
The bookkeeper and me are driving away.
簿記員將和我駕車離開
See? Or else he dies.He dies, and you aingt got nothing
如果他死了 你們就什麼都沒了
You got five seconds to make up your mind.
給你們五秒鐘決定
I'll tell ya what ya want to know! Shut up! I'm not kidding
我告訴你們…我告訴你們所想知道的一切 閉嘴 我不是說著玩
He's crazy! Don't let him do this, I'll tell you what you want to know!
殺了他 我什麼都告訴你們
You got him? Yeah, I got him.
你瞄準他了 是的 我瞄準了
One! Will you stop it!
一 請你們制止他
Take him.
解決他
Two.
二
The two coded entries in this ledger
這帳本上的記號代表了收付物件
represent cash disbursement to all levels of city officials,
包括了各級政府官員、員警人員
members of the police and to Alphonse Capone.
還有艾爾卡彭 是不是
That's correct. Excuse me?
沒錯 你說什麼
I said that is correct.
你說得沒錯
And you will decipher these coded entries for us?
而你會替我們譯出帳本上的代號
I will.
是的
Sorry, Mr Payne, I can't hear you.
對不起 佩恩先生 我聽不到
I said, I will.
是的 我會
You were in charge of disbursements for Mr Capone?
你負責替卡彭先生管帳
Yes, I was.
是的
And you personally distributed monies vast, undeclared monies to Mr Capone?
而你是親自將那些 未報稅的鉅款交給卡彭先生
Yes, I did.
是的
Would you tell us the amounts?
你能告訴我們總數嗎?
In a three-year period I personally disbursed monies to Mr Capone
三年來 我親自交給卡彭先生
in excess of one and a third million dollars.
一百三十多萬元
Would you repeat that amount, please?
請你再重複一次
One and a third million dollars. Thank you very much.
一百三十萬美元 謝謝你
I don't understand it. What does Capone have?
我不明白 卡彭為何有恃無恐
We're nailing the lid on his coffin, and he's smiling.
他一直在微笑
The son-of-a-bitch is wearing a gun in court.
那傢伙在法庭上帶槍
Get me the bailiff.
叫法警來
It'll be a fast trial.
很快會結束的
The man in the front row wearing a white suit is carrying a gun.
那個穿白西裝的人身上帶了把槍
I don't want this to turn into something. I'll lead you out.
我不希望在此鬧事 你叫他出去
Could we speak to you a minute, please?
請你出來一下好嗎
Get up against it. You heard him. Now, up against it!
面對牆壁 你以為你是誰? 你聽到他的話了
What's this? Empty all your pockets, all of it.
好了 把口袋掏空放在這裡 全拿出來
I've got a permit for that. Fine, let's see it.
我有帶槍的許可 我看看
I'm not the one under indictment. Everything on the table.
遭起訴的人不是我 把東西放在桌上
Let me see. Give him his gun back.
把槍還他
"To Whom It May Concern. Please extend to the bearer, "
請給予弗蘭克尼蒂先生一切的方便和工作
"Mr Frank Nitti, all possible courtesy and consideration."
主席弗蘭克運往尼提，所有可能的禮遇和照顧
"W illiam Thompson, Mayor of the City of Chicago."
威廉湯姆森 芝加哥市長
I'm sorry, Mr Ness, you'll have to give it back.
對不起 奈斯先生 你必須把槍還他
Fine. But that man does not go back into that courtroom.
好吧 但那傢伙不准再進入法庭
Do you understand me? Yes, sir.
你明白嗎 是的 長官
“拉辛路1634號”
1634 Racine... You know, I used to have a friend who lived there.
拉辛路1634號 我曾有位朋友住在那裡
Don't. Let him go.
不要 讓他走
No! Here, take it.
不要
Here I am, Treasury Man. Come on! Harass me!
我在這裡 財政官員 來呀 逮捕我
What are you waiting for?
你在等什麼
Don't just stand there! Harass me!
別光站在那裡 逮捕我呀
Don't push me.
別惹火了我
They're gonna burn you, buddy. Yeah?
我要送你下地獄 老兄 是嗎
Yeah. I'm gonna come see you burn, you son-of-a-bitch!
沒錯 我要看你下獄
'Cause you killed my friend!
因為你殺了我朋友
He died like a pig. What did you say?
他死得像只豬一樣 你說什麼
I said that your friend died screaming like a stuck Irish pig.
我說你朋友死前哀號得像豬一樣
Now you think about that when I beat the rap.
等我脫罪時 你慢慢想吧
Did he sound anything like that?
像你這樣嗎?
One picture, come on, one picture.
拍張照 拍張照
Mr Ness, take a look at this.
奈斯 看看這個
Mr Ness?
奈斯先生
Mr Ness, are you doing okay? I think you'd better see this.
奈斯先生 你還好吧? 你最好看看這個
What is it? That's the jury list, Mr Ness.
這是什麼 這是陪審團名單
They've been bribed.
他們被收買了
I got it out of Nitti's coat. Where is Nitti?
從尼蒂西裝裡搜出來的 尼蒂呢?
He's in the car.
他在車上
This constitutes no evidence. I'm not about to allow...
這不構成證據 沒有用 我可不准許
Your Honour, the truth is that Capone is a killer and he will go free.
庭上 這案子的事實是 卡彭是個殺人兇手 而你卻要讓他自由
There is only one way to deal with such men, and that is hunt them down.
對付他這種人只有一種辦法 便是把他關起來
I have. I have forsworn myself. I have broken laws I swore to defend.
我曾發誓 我要不計任何方法捉住被告
I am content that I have done right. That man must be stopped, you must...
我很滿意我所做的正確方法 那個人必須被制止 而你一定要…
I'll be the judge of what I must do, Mr Ness.
我是法官 我會盡我的責任 奈斯先生
Would you excuse us?
請你們出去好嗎
Bailiff. Yes, sir.
法警 是的
I want you to go next door to Judge Hoffman's Court,
我要你去隔壁霍法官的法庭
where they've just begun hearing a divorce action.
他們剛開始審理離婚案件
I want you to bring that jury in here and take this jury to his court.
我要你把他的陪審團帶來 把這裡的陪審團帶過去
Are those instructions clear? Yes, sir, they're clear.
你聽清楚了嗎 是的 庭上
What's he talking about?
他說什麼
Bailiff, I want you to switch the juries.
我要你調換陪審團 是的
Your Honour, I object!
我抗議
Overruled.
駁回
What did you tell him?
你是怎麼說動他的
I told him his name was in the ledger, too.
我說他的名字也在帳本上
His name wasn't in the ledger!
但他的名字並不在帳本上
Wait a second! Is this the law? What's going on here?
等等 這就是法律嗎 怎麼回事
You're out of order. What's going on?
- 請守秩序 - 發生了什麼事
I think...
我認為
OK.What you think... Do something here.
我不管你認為什麼 想點辦法
What do I look like to you? Do something
我看起來像什麼? 想點辦法呀
Order!
秩序
Your Honour, we'd like to withdraw our plea of Not Guilty,
庭上 我們撤回無罪申辯
and enter a plea of Guilty.
改為有罪申辯
Guilty? Order in the court!
維持庭上秩序
Order!
秩序
Bailiff, clear the courtroom!
法警 維持秩序
Your Honour! Is that justice?
庭上 庭上 這公正嗎
Please, why did he switch the jury?
他為何調換陪審團?
Are you gonna go after the organisation?
你有何打算? 你打算繼續
Excuse me.
借光
I'm asking Your Honour, is this justice?
那是公正嗎?
Is this justice?
這樣公正嗎
Never stop fighting till the fight is done.
絕不停止 絕不停止戰鬥 直到戰鬥終止
What did you say?
你說什麼
I said, never stop fighting till the fight is done.
我說絕不停止戰鬥 直到戰鬥停止為止
What? You heard me, Capone. It's over.
你聽到我的話了 卡彭 都結束了
You're nothing but a lot of talk and a badge.
滾開 你只會說大話
Here endeth the lesson.
最後一課
You're nothing but a lot of talk and a badge!
你只知道口出狂言
“不可動搖者打擊罪犯”
“奈斯保證不被收買”
“卡彭今天出庭”
“卡彭被判十一年徒刑”
So much violence.
太多暴力了
Cleaning up a little.
總算清理了一點
I guess this is goodbye.
我想該說再見了
Goodbye, George.
再見 喬治
I want to...thank you for this.
我要感謝你
No. Thank you.
不 謝謝你
Mr Ness... I think he would have wanted you to have that.
奈斯先生 我認為他希望你能保有的
He'd have wanted a cop to have it.
他希望送給員警
I'm going home.
我要回家了
Mr Ness! Any comment for the record?
奈斯先生 你對這標題有何意見
'The man who put Al Capone on the spot.'
捉拿卡彭下獄的人
I just happened to be there when the wheel went round.
我只是適逢其時而已
They say they're going to repeal prohibition.
聽說禁酒令將取消
What will you do then? I think I'll have a drink.
你會怎麼做? 也許我會去喝上一杯